bluewiremedia.com.au 2019-03-19

# GDPR Compliance & Privacy Policy - Bluewire Media

## GDPR Compliance

### The steps we’re taking to ensure Bluewire Media Pty Ltd is fully prepared for GDPR include:

  * Reviewing and auditing our internal processes, procedures, data systems, and documentation
  * Evaluating and implementing new features that give Bluewire Media subscribers and students greater control of and access to their data
  * Reviewing the GDPR-friendliness of our website and CRM.

## Privacy Policy

### Owner and Data Controller (The ‘Owner’)

Bluewire Media Pty Ltd,  
**ACN** : 115 735 192.  
Our website address is: https://bluewiremedia.com.au.  
**CEO is Adam Franklin** adam.franklin [at] bluewiremedia.com.au

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### The rights of Users

Users may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by the Owner.

In particular, Users have the right to do the following:

  * **Withdraw their consent at any time.**  Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to the processing of their Personal Data.
  * **Object to processing of their Data.**  Users have the right to object to the processing of their Data if the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent. Further details are provided in the dedicated section below.
  * **Access their Data.**  Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the Owner, obtain disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing processing.
  * **Verify and seek rectification.**  Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.
  * **Restrict the processing of their Data.**  Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to restrict the processing of their Data. In this case, the Owner will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it.
  * **Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed.**  Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to obtain the erasure of their Data from the Owner.
  * **Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller.**  Users have the right to receive their Data in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and, if technically feasible, to have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance. This provision is applicable provided that the Data is processed by automated means and that the processing is based on the User’s consent, on a contract which the User is part of or on pre-contractual obligations thereof.
  * **Lodge a complaint.**  Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority.

### Details about the right to object to processing

Where Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority vested in the Owner or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner, Users may object to such processing by providing a ground related to their particular situation to justify the objection.

Users must know that, however, should their Personal Data be processed for direct marketing purposes, they can object to that processing at any time without providing any justification. To learn, whether the Owner is processing Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, Users may refer to the relevant sections of this document.

### How to exercise these rights

Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner through the contact details provided in this document. These requests can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed by the Owner as early as possible and always within one month.

### Information we collect via forms

We collect information you provide directly to us. For example, we collect information when you create an account, participate in any interactive features of the Services, subscribe to a newsletter or email list, participate in an event, survey, contest or promotion, make a purchase, communicate with us via third-party social media sites, request customer support or otherwise communicate with us.

The types of information we may collect include your name, email address, password, postal address, phone number, occupation, photo, payment information (such as your credit or debit card and billing address), preference or interest data, and any other information you choose to provide.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Who we share your data with

We never sell your data with anyone.  Your data sits on GDPR-compliant databases with Sumo, Infusionsoft, LeadPages, PayPal, WordPress, Webinar Ninja, Google Analytics and Zippy Courses.

  * **Infusionsoft** is a User database management service provided by Infusion Software, Inc. Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. Place of processing: US –[Privacy Policy](https://www.infusionsoft.com/legal/privacy-policy).
  * **Zippy Courses** is an Online Course Plugin operated by DHJW Software LLC dba “Zippy Courses™. Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service [Privacy Policy.](https://zippycoursesplugin.com/privacy-policy/)
  * **Sumo** is a business growth software tool provided by Sumo Group Inc,. Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service [Privacy Policy.](https://help.sumo.com/hc/en-us/articles/218958727-Privacy-Policy)
  * **PayPal** is a payment service provided by PayPal Inc., which allows Users to make online payments using their PayPal credentials.Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. [Privacy Policy.](https://www.paypal.com/au/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full)
  * **Leadpages** is landing Page software where users can provide their email address to receive one of our free documents.Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service [Privacy Policy.](https://www.leadpages.net/privacy)
  * **Webinar Ninja** is a webinar platforms where users can provide their details to register for a webinar.Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service [Privacy Policy](https://webinarninja.com/privacy/).
  * **WordPress** is a website platform where users can provide their details to leave comments. Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service [Privacy Policy.](https://en-au.wordpress.org/about/privacy/)
  * **Google Analytics** is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.  Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

### How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

### What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.
